The story that is about to begin
took place halfway through the 1990s.
While a bit of dramatizing is an
occupational vice and can't be helped,
we inform you that the story is based
on true events we ourselves witnessed.
On a country road, in winter...
Kotaro!
The phone.
Who?
Tachihara.
Yes...
I'm awake...
Yeah...
Yeah... where?
You serious?!
Yes... Yes...
Someone's lying on the road
near the elementary school.
Really?
It snowed last night.
Okay, Grandpa, let's go have a pee.
It's cold...
Oh, Hikari!
What're you doing?
Be careful. I cracked up the car.
Early shift?
No, it looks like someone collapsed.
Really?
The Matsugane Potshot Affair
This side first.
All right.
Oh.
The ice pick.
It was in a bag lying near her body.
She was probably carrying it.
Could've caused that.
Show me.
It's over here.
Excuse me.
Ah, Tachihara?
She's alive.
Huh?
"Suzuki Dairy"
"Fuji Box Lunches"
That man's hopeless.
C'mon, Yoko
Your poor father,
calling him "that man"!
He was in a state yesterday.
How's that?
The Mama at Eden Club told me.
She said he got plastered,
grabbed her, saying how lonely he is.
She really can't stand that.
But really, it's hard to imagine...
not being allowed to
see your granddaughter.
It's not a matter of allowing
him to see her or not.
It amounts to that.
You know...
Yoko could be more...
It's not Yoko... well, it's Yoko too,
but think of her mother.
Her feelings matter the most.
Hey, Hikari.
Hi.
Quit dragging about!
Hurry and eat!
Stay away from the melon.
It smells bad.
Did you hear? Somebody died today.
Out past White Vegas,
near the school.
An accident?
I'm not sure. It was a women, young.
Oh, a suicide.
Why suicide, if it's a women?
What are you doing?
Tsurukichi, what are you up to?
She asked me to have a look.
Is that true, Haruko?
Yes.
- You're lying.
- Yes.
C'mon, pull up your pants.
Yes.
Tsurukichi!
It's not that, maybe.
Enough. Let's go.
- Yeah.
- Maybe, it's not what you think...
Pull up your pants!
Yes.
Haruko, what did Tsurukichi do?
He looked and put it in.
Put what in?
A mechanical pencil.
Let's go!
Hurry!
Why did you drop your pants?
Well...
He said I look like Aratama Michiyo.
Who's Aratama Michiyo?
Never heard of her.
And when you turned around,
the car was upon you?
That's right.
Were you walking
in the field, Ms. Ikeuchi?
Or were you walking on the road?
The field?
That's right.
- The road?
- That's right.
Oh...
Ms. Ikeuchi...
It really doesn't matter, does it?
Of course it matters, ma'am,
you're the victim of a hit-and-run.
Well, I'm not dead, so who cares?
That's not the issue here.
It was a hit-and-run,
so the circumstances...
What is it you want from me?
Tell me how the accident happened.
I don't remember!
What do you expect?
I was the one who was hit!
Yes, of course...
So, then...
Now, now, Ms. Ikeuchi...
What?
Here, this, and this...
Was this all you had?
That's right.
An ice pick... an ice pick.
- What about it?
- Well...
Ordinary people can't buy ice picks?
You're imagining things.
Well, it's not that...
I'm the victim here.
That's right.
How come you bully me?
I'm defenseless.
I'm not bullying you.
You are too.
Ms. Ikeuchi, I'm not bullying...
Now, now... I'll put them away.
See, I'm putting them away.
See, I put them away.
Ms. Ikeuchi!
If you happen to remember anything,
just give me a call...
Oh, it's pointless!
"Welcome to Matsugane"
"Home of the Wild Boar Legend"
An experienced flenser, or whale
butcher, accompanied the survey.
He carved the whale into small pieces.
A veteran knife carver with
more than 30 years experience,
his is a skill passed down
across the generations.
Ouch!
Ah!
- Ow!
- What were you up to?
I was hit by a car.
I spent a night in the hospital.
This is too much!
That hurts... not there...
That's not the spot...
That's too hard...
What is that there?
Wild boar meat.
They announced it,
free for the taking.
You got it for free?
What were you thinking!?
You got it, now who'll cook it?
Where are you going to cook it?
Mice again?
Yeah...
Here...
Oh, thanks.
They've got a way of getting in here.
Yeah...
It was a hit-and-run.
What was?
The accident yesterday.
Oh...
She regained consciousness.
When you think about it...
Yeah?
It could have been more interesting.
Yeah. Just a hit-and-run.
Right...
Coming back from the dead
was a good start...
You really shouldn't say that.
Huh?
Welcome!
The Special.
Okay.
Ow!!
We'd live at your mother's house?
Yeah.
That a promise?
Not really...
But, there's Hikari...
I don't mind, but he might
be uncomfortable...
I wouldn't want that.
Ahh...
And I want a baby before I'm 30.
Yeah...
Do you like that?
I like that.
Let me inside.
No.
Can I come inside?
Please.
Then do that first.
Yeah.
It's no good, this guy's broke.
How much do you have in the bank?
Give me a break!
How much?!
Please! I beg you!
Hit-and-run guy!
Please!
Ow!
Turn around!
What's this?
Hmm...
You wind it here.
Smile!
1 million for each photo.
I'm really sorry, I will confess...
I'll go to the police.
And they will pay?
Eh?
What?!
Go to the police, we get insurance money.
You think that makes it ok?
Not at all.
I'll do whatever you want.
You do have money in the bank, right?
There's no way I can
sleep at the station...
Really, I'm flat broke.
Ah, it's cold.
That's dangerous! Watch out!
Watch out!
Okay, sell your car, right away.
There... there's...
...a place you can stay.
A place...
What's the story here?
Ah, my grandpa used to live here.
There's no one here now.
Will there really be power tomorrow?
I'll get it done.
Gas and water, too.
I don't like places like this.
I understand...
You know what you did?
Let's hear it.
Yes.
I hit her with my car.
Miyuki, what did he do to you?
Yes.
This man crushed me with his car.
It's only right that we stay here.
- Yes.
- All right.
The photos...
You double-cross us or try anything
stupid, I give them to the police.
And I'll put the squeeze on you.
Not just you, but your whole family.
I'll destroy your lives.
This is not a threat. It's a promise.
I always honour my promises.
You'd better too.
Yeah.
So, what about it?
Yeah, I'm thinking it over.
You're not thinking about anything.
Of course I am, I'm thinking it over.
She's a nice girl.
She was very helpful today.
It all depends on Kotaro.
That's no way to talk, right, Kotaro?
This one, she's a realist.
With marriage, you have to be.
Give me a break!
Here she comes!
Naked? Come here!
Up you go! Here you are!
I'm sorry.
- Was she sassy?
- Not at all.
If she's sassy, spank her.
"I get my way all the time!
I'm a spoiled little girl!"
So, I heard Toyo's gone back to her.
He's back with Izumi?
Aoyama went for a haircut,
saw him there.
I wish he'd just die.
I've given up. It's like
a sickness with him.
In fact, he might really be sick.
Well, Toyo has a lot on his mind.
Right?
That's not what you said to Aoyama.
- Well...
- And stop calling him Toyo.
"Izumi's Hair Salon"
Toyo,
I keep telling you, it's true.
But she's always been fat.
there's no change.
I wonder who the father is.
She won't say?
Not a word.
You don't know, do you?
I thought maybe you'd know.
Me? Why would I?
You'd know from experience.
You did it with her when I was out?
I thought so.
Why didn't you know earlier?
She didn't say a word, foolish girl.
She's already 7 months.
I'd think you would have noticed.
What do you know?
It's your fault anyway.
Hello!
I'm coming.
It's too late to abort.
She's having the baby, see?
Sorry to keep you.
Hikari.
Give it to me.
Push it in.
Hey, it's really there.
I can't do it.
Go.
What's this?!
Stop! Don't kill me!
I won't tell anyone! I won't tell.
Ow! Stop! I'm sorry!
I won't tell anyone! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I won't! Don't kill me!
I don't want to die! No!
It's been tough, but it's over now.
Right?
See you.
Hey... ah...
about those photos...
Here.
Here, thank you.
Yes.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Well, then... er...
could I see some identification?
And yours... would you mind?
"Shibuya Urology Clinic"
Yes, I see.
Well, then. We'll have to
have these appraised.
We'll hold on to them
for a few days.
This gold has to be tested at
headquarters to see if it's pure.
Headquarters?
Yes. Or, well, at the SLCB.
The SLCB?
The SLCB.
I'll give you a receipt for the gold.
I'll call you when the appraisal
is done, like that...
Okay, then...
Ah... these...
how did you get them, or...
No, that's ok, it's all right, okay...
They'll know when they look it up.
Oh, do you have the statement?
What?
Ah, something that shows
you purchased these, a receipt...
I don't.
You don't?
I didn't... know.
Ah, you didn't...
Ah...
no good.
Okay.
Okay?
We're ok.
- A mistake.
- Oh, a mistake
Welcome home?
What are you doing!?
Nothing special.
Why not turn on the lights?
I didn't want to bother.
Want some dinner?
I didn't cook the rice.
Oh, Grandpa, you've been at it again!
It sticks better when it's cold.
Stop this nonsense.
Want to order sushi?
What's going on?
Why?
Something's strange.
These stick better
when they're cold, too.
What's going on?
You're...
going to be a big brother.
Huh?
How does that make you feel?
What are you talking about?
Your father's child.
But...
How old is Izumi?
No...
it's Haruko.
What!?
Welcome home.
I'm so ashamed, I can't show my face.
We're off now.
Be careful.
See you later!
Yeah.
It's been a while...
How've you been?
Is that right?
Did you do it with Haruko?
- Did Izumi tell you?
- Did you do it?
- Did Haruko tell you?
- What did mother say?
- Did you do it?
Everyone knows?
So, did you do it with Haruko?
Whether you'd call it that...
You're a fool!
What will you do?
It just happened,
and nothing can change that.
You know what you've done?
I know.
Ah, what should I do?
Don't turn to us for help.
That's what mother said.
Did you really do it
with my old man?
Yes.
You'd do it with anyone, right?
You did it with Tsurukichi?
Yes.
You sure he's the father?
Don't be stupid.
What are you doing here?
Oh... didn't I tell you?
He's a friend from my time
in Tokyo.
Tokyo?
Yeah, well...
Yeah...
A friend from back then, right?
I see.
Oh... didn't I tell you?
This guy's, ah... his girlfriend.
Right?
I see...
What?
Who was that?
Hold on!
What are you cooking up?
He's my brother...
my little brother.
Why is he a policeman?
He's a cop.
He's a cop and my brother.
Huh?
Sorry...
But he's all right.
After all, we're twins.
- Huh?
- We're twins, so it's ok.
No need to worry.
Sorry.
And we need 200,000 yen.
There, all set.
- Okay.
- Here.
Thanks.
How about today?
Okay, five thousand more.
She's getting big,
don't make her do anything weird.
Okay, I got it.
Haruko!
Oh, Haruko!
Relax a bit more...
Slide your butt over...
Slide on down here...
I'm putting it in now.
Relax now, does that hurt?
Are you ok? Does that hurt?
It's okay.
Relax, spread your legs.
Raise your hips higher.
Raise your head and
say it to my face!
Like I said...
it was just an advance.
What's going on?
He stole money from us.
What?
Not just from the office.
Grandpa's cash is gone.
I just borrowed it.
Grandpa said it was ok...
What!?
Grandpa doesn't know which end's up!
What were you going
to use the money for?
I won't be angry. Tell the truth.
He has a women.
A women?
Has her staying at Grandpa's.
Not just a women.
Some strange man too.
I don't like what they're up to.
You saw them?
Everyone has.
Don't you know anything?
You're so pie-in-the-sky, mother.
You've always spoiled Hikari.
He does as he pleases,
leaves me with the dirty work.
You think I took over
the farm because I enjoy it?
Taking care of cows
from dawn to dark,
that filthy work,
do you have any idea how hard it is?
He helps at his whim,
then steals from us.
He makes a fool of us
for working hard!
What are you smiling about?!
Hikari has...
Shut up!
Yoko, calm down, that's enough.
I can't stand it!
I really did the best I could...
What more could I do?
Kotaro, do something!
They were bound to find out.
Stick out your foot.
My foot?
Your foot.
How big?
27.
Mine are 26.
That's a lie. They're really 25.5.
We may be twins,
but we're totally different.
I never thought they'd find out.
Those people, who are they?
Are they really friends from Tokyo?
You only spent a month in Tokyo...
and you were so lonely there.
Hikari.
Hikari...
Umm...
Hi, Beiyan.
- Come here a sec.
- Why?
- What's up?
- Just come on...
What?
Well, ah... it's about this house.
It actually belongs
to our grandfather...
We rented it out once...
but now, we keep it vacant.
But that doesn't change the fact
that it's still a Suzuki house.
So, ah, Hikari's free to
use it as he pleases, but...
well, after all...
So?
Well, it's about time...
you know, to, ah...
What is it?
We're not welcome.
No, not at all.
I'm not saying that.
Just that, maybe you've
stayed long enough.
Who is he?
Authority?
Yeah, come to force us out.
No, this has nothing to do with it.
I came dressed like this,
but... I'm not here as a policeman,
I'm here as a Suzuki.
Did Suzuki Hikari send him?
No, he doesn't know
anything about it.
I'm here as a member
of the Suzuki family...
Why is it?
He said, "Stay as long as you want."
Why do we have to listen to this?
Did Hikari really say that?
He did.
Just ask him.
Did you talk with him before
coming here?
Yes.
You said he didn't know anything.
I didn't tell him I was coming here.
Well, you should talk
to Suzuki Hikari first.
That's the first step,
before talking to us.
This place belongs to
the Suzuki family, not Hikari.
What, now he's threatening us?
I'm not threatening.
That is a threat.
It is a threat, unquestionably.
Carrying that pistol-like thing...
It's a threat.
You can't have a conversation
with someone carrying a gun.
Please, talk it over
with Suzuki Hikari.
Good-bye.
Grandpa!
Why put these in the fridge?
Grandpa, are you awake?
Shall we go for a pee?
Grandpa?
"In Mourning"
Here.
How old was he, the old man?
Eighty... Three?
It was a peaceful death.
A good way to go.
This is tough.
My dentures will come out.
Since when did you get dentures?
We're getting up there ourselves.
It's so quiet...
It's like a wake.
Yoko and Keiichi went home.
And where are the boys?
Nobody here.
Maybe I'll move back there again.
Yeah...
Maybe that's a good idea.
The tournament began in 1990...
and is now in its fifth year.
Curling uses stones that
are made in Scotland...
Please stop over there for us.
Your father has asked you.
Please, Kotaro.
Help me out here, ok?
It's for your mother's sake too.
He's using you!
Please stop over there.
Help me out, please.
Kotaro...
I'm changing rounds.
Here...
Your father? How is he?
Yeah, okay.
Is that right...
Kotaro, tell your father to
show his face now and then.
Haruko's waiting for him. All right?
Yes.
Kotaro.
Is this it?
Hikari...
sold this to you?
He said it would make me popular,
but it didn't work.
I'm fucked...
That would be fraud,
right, if it came out.
I wouldn't want that,
so I wanted to talk with you.
Thanks.
But you really believed him.
He said it would work.
What did you pay for it?
What 20,000?
200,000.
We don't go out drinking anymore.
He's hanging out with bad apples.
Toilet.
This is no good.
No good at all.
What?
Let's go to the police.
But you promised.
I thought you'd take care of it.
I can't.
What'll happen to me?
I go to prison for a hit-and-run?
They'll kill me!
Don't worry. The women didn't die.
No. I can't.
You don't understand...
what kind of people they are.
You just don't get it.
They have photos too.
Photos?
No! I just can't!
What, then?
I don't know! Don't ask me.
Kotaro, why did you
revive that women?
Why did you run into her?!
Hikari.
Hey, stop the car.
Okay, easy, easy... I'll steer.
Stop the car. Okay, brakes.
That's it, spit it out.
Spit it all out, all of it.
Kotaro!
What're you doing?
Setsuko's family is here!
What?
Well, we work with animals,
but these days there are machines.
In fact, I leave the farm to
my daughter and her husband.
To hear them complain about how
hard the work is, drives me crazy.
In my father's day, it was done like this.
Now with the machine, it's a breeze.
One, two, three, and swoosh.
What's so tough about that?
In that sense, I prefer the cows.
They don't complain,
just make babies and produce milk.
Of course, cows can't talk, but...
Oh, hi.
- Ah...
- Oh, hello.
What kept you?
Sorry to keep you waiting...
Are you working?
Ah... sorry, dressed like this.
Setsuko, come here a minute.
Excuse us please.
What is it.
Kotaro!
Why are you here today?
Didn't you hear?
Not a thing.
Our plane changed. I called and
your mum said to come today.
What's the idea?!
I can't deal with this now.
How can you say that?
Ah, it's all right.
Okay.
When my wife died...
How old were you? In middle school.
Second year.
She was the only female in the house,
so we relied on her,
left all household chores to her...
She would rather have
been playing with friends,
She tells us now, many years later...
Well, what you might
call self-reliance...
That spirit is something that's
born of adversity, or so it seems.
In Setsuko's case...
as I understand it,
losing her mother at an early age,
well, maybe that turned out
to be a good thing in the end.
Now, Kotaro has an
older twin, named Hikari.
Officially Hikari's registered
as the older brother,
but my wife insists otherwise.
She totally believes this guy
came out first.
Well, I then started to think my
wife could be right about this...
as she was the one that gave
birth to both of them afterall.
This guy has a better personality and a
stronger sense of responsibility...
and he's very serious.
Well, a policeman without
resposibility would be a problem...
though mostly he sits at the police
box and rides around on his bike.
Well, still... I mean, it's not
a job just anyone can do.
Right? Right?
We need to have a serious talk.
Yeah...
Why did you lie like that?
Lie?
I'm the older brother,
responsible and all that.
Oh, things like that,
you put the best spin on them.
I'm your father,
I know how it works...
Go home!
This is my home!
Get lost, is what I'm saying.
Self-reliance! What in the world?
You have no right to lecture!
After what you did with Haruko,
you've got some nerve!
Where's the proof that
the baby is mine?
When did I do it with Haruko?
Were you there?
What?!
Izumi makes money off
Haruko, you know that.
Why blame me for
getting her pregnant?
Well, but...
Kotaro.
Yeah?
You too, right?
I know.
You think I didn't notice,
but I know all about it.
Ah, you are the younger brother.
Kotaro.
I'm going to take care of this...
I'm sorry I've always depended on you.
But now...
now I'm...
getting my act together.
If I don't do it myself,
nothing will change...
right?
Kotaro,
thanks for everything.
Nishioka!
Mr. Nishioka.
How long are you going to stay here?
What do you want?
I mean, why am I the one who
has to put up with this crap?
Come on, now, take your gold bars,
and get out of here, please!
I don't know, but...
you screwed up everything.
It's all your fault.
You found the gold,
but you couldn't cash it in.
So why did you come back?
You need to get tough, baldy!
You... you made me build that oven,
you made me melt the gold,
then you gave up when
you saw the melted gold.
It's all because of you!
It's all your fault!
If you'd just disappear,
that would be fine by me!
Die!
Don't pull it out!
Stop! Don't pull it out!
If you do, you'll die.
Morning...
Good morning!
Yes...
Good morning.
Morning.
Good morning!
Hi, g'morning.
Oh, you caught up?
- Morning
- Take care now.
Tachihara.
Yeah?
We've got to get them at the source.
What? Mice again?
It won't do to catch
them one at a time.
Until we cut off the source,
they'll keep coming.
Are you sure there are any?
I've never seen one.
There definatley are.
I hear them run across the ceiling.
You're the only one who hears them.
What?
Relax.
I'm joking, joking.
Definatley...
we've got to cut them
off at the source.
Yeah...
Oh, Kotaro!
Haruko's about to give birth,
all of a sudden.
Okay.
- Your father is coming.
- Come on hurry.
- Tell your mother when she gets home.
- Hurry!
Please.
She's giving birth.
Haruko?
Nothing can be done.
The mice just multiply.
"Building and Water Department"
Mr. Ueshima...
What is it?
That man.
Yes?
- Ah, I'd like to inquire...
- Yes.
I want to mix this poison
into the water.
I need to be sure all the water
in town has this mixed into it.
This area uses water
from the lake, right?
Put it in there, it'd get mixed in?
Oh, no.
- If we put it in there, it'll get filtered.
- Well...
The purification plant.
We could mix it in there.
Excuse me, ah...
Half measures won't do.
We have to cut them off
at the source.
If even one gets through,
they'll just multiply...
The water reservoirs,
the reservoirs would work...
How many are there?
Must be quite a few...
There's one on Mt. Unesawa, right?
Ah, there's a dam up there.
But a dam would be ok...
"We Use Real Gold!"
"Matsugane Souvenir Lucky Key Holder"
"Nishioka Yuji and Miyuki"
Hey. Welcome back.
Hey.
Sorry.
I'm all right now. Sorry...
The Matsugane Potshot Affair
Arai Hirofumi
Yamanaka Takashi
Kawagoe Miwa
Kimura Yuichi
Ando Yamae
Kimura Midoriko
Nishio Mari
Kang Soo Eun
Karasuma Setsuko
Miura Tomokazu
Enoki Hyoe
Nakamura Yoshihiro
Suzuki Chikako
Uda Teppei
Mitsuishi Ken
Den Den
Produced by
Yamagami Tetsujiro
Executive producers
Owada Hiroki
Sadai Yuji
Oshima Mitsuru
Line producer
Watanabe Eiji
Associate producer
Okamoto Haruo
Production manager
Sasaki Masaaki
Screenplay by
Mukai Kosuke
Sato Kumiko
Yamashita Nobuhiro
Cinematography by
Tsutai Takahiro
Lighting by
Hikita Yoshitake
Sound by
Ogawa Takeshi
Production design by
Aiko Etsuko
Set decoration by
Tatsuta Tetsuji
Editing by
Miyajima Ryuji
Kikui Takashige
Music by
Rocket Matsu, Pascals
Assistant director
Ishikawa Hisashi
Assistant line producer
Morisaki Yuji
Casting by
Nishikawa Fumiro
Costumes by
Kobayashi Miwako
Makeup by
Tokuda Michiyo
End theme music
"Molecicco" performed by Boredoms
Subtitles based on English translation by
John Junkerman
Original subtitle producer
Passo Passo
Subtitle editing, additions, new timings for
this version by chochoc
Additional English translations by
Starclub, zen
Special thanks to koji
Directed by
Yamashita Nobuhiro